In order to launch the turtlesim package,
turtlesim パッケージを起動するには
you must first ensure that all of the ROS environment variables have been correctly set.
まず すべての ROS 環境変数が正しく設定されていることを確認する必要があります
Each ROS distribution provides a handy little script called setup.bash,
それぞれの ROS ディストリビューションは
specifically for this purpose.
setup.bash と呼ばれる便利な小さなスクリプトを提供しています
The script is hidden away in the Opt ROS kinetic directory and you
スクリプトは Opt ROS キネティック ディレクトリに隠されており
can run it with the bash command source.
bash コマンド ソースで実行することができます
Among other things,
とりわけ
the environment variables tell our bash shell
環境変数は bash シェル
where ROS commands and packages can be found.
に ROS コマンドとパッケージを見つけることができる場所を伝えます
One simple way to determine if the environment variables have been
環境変数が
set is to use the bash tab completion feature,
設定されているかどうかを判断する簡単な方法の一つは bash タブ補完機能を使用することです
typing ROS followed by double tapping
ROS を入力した後にダブルタップ
the tab key gives us an extensive list of all commands beginning
タブキーを押すと
with the characters R-O-S. And there we go, there's our list.
R-O-S で開始する すべてのコマンドの一覧が表示されますこれがリストです
This list would be much shorter had we not sourced as ROSsetup.bash.
このリストは ROSsetup.bash として調達していなければ はるかに短くなります
Later on in this module we'll become more familiar with some of the commands listed here.
このモジュールの後半では ここにリストされているコマンドのいくつかを詳しく知ることができます
Having to source the ROSsetup.bash script for
開いたそれぞれの新しい端末に対して ROSsetup.bash スクリプトを入手しなければならないのは
each new terminal you open is quickly going to become painful.
すぐに大変になります
To combat the monotony we can add the command to sourceSetup.bash to our bash RC file.
単調さに対抗するために sourceSetup.bash へのコマンドを bash RC ファイルに追加します
Bash RC, is simply a shell script that is
Bash RC は単に bash セッションを開始するたびに自動的に実行される
automatically run whenever you start a bash session.
シェル スクリプトです
Now, when we open a new terminal and type ROS tab tab,
新しい端末を開いて ROS タブのタブを入力すると
we'll see the long list of ROS core commands.
ROS コア コマンドの長いリストが表示されます
There we go, there is our list.
これがリストです
And that's it for setting up your environment.
これは 環境を整えるためのものです
You're now ready to run the turtlesim.
turtlesim を実行する準備が整いました